Guide to the Allan Cox Papers SC0343
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Allan Cox papers
1954-1987
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Cox, Allan
SC0343
20.25 Linear Feet
Papers document his professional life as teacher, administrator, and researcher and include correspondence; memoranda; research notes, charts, proposals, and reports; grant applications; outlines, tests, lecture notes, and other teaching materials; manuscripts; minutes; date books; papers and theses by his students; reprints; maps; and his notes while a student at UC Berkeley. Cox studied paleomagnetism and plate tectonics theory; some materials pertain to research done on the Galapagos Islands and in China.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The son of a house painter, Allan attended high school in Santa Ana. He pursued his education through independent reading during 3 years in the merchant marine (1945-48), 3 years of undergraduate chemistry at the University of California at Berkeley (1948-51), and 2 more years of independent reading as a private in the U.S. Army (1951-53). The most important event in his education, and the one that helped him choose geology as a career, was a summer job with the U.S. Geological Survey in 1950 as a field assistant to Clyde Wahrhaftig in Alaska. Allan received his B.A. (1955), M.A. (1957), and Ph.D. (1959) degrees from the University of California at Berkeley, where he was inspired by the teaching of John Verhoogen and Perry Byerly. He began his professional career at the U.S. Geological Survey in Menlo Park, where he helped establish what was to become one of the most successful paleomagnetic laboratories in the country. From 1959 to 1967 he worked as a geophysicist with the U.S. Geological Survey. In 1967 he joined the faculty at Stanford University, where he became Cecil and Ida Green Professor of Geophysics. He was elected to the National Academy of Sciences in 1969 and to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences in 1974. He became president of the American Geophysical Union in 1978. He received the Fleming Medal of the American Geophysical Union (1969), the Day Medal of the Geological Society of America (1975), and the Vetlesen Prize (1971). In 1979 he became the dean of the School of Earth Sciences. He was an author of over 100 papers in learned scientific journals. He established our Master's degree program in exploration geophysics, and was mentor to many students.
The essence of Allan Cox is a rare quality -- the ability and determination to bring out the very best in others. To a degree we've never seen in another person with his achievements, he had a most wonderful mix of personal humility with demanding standards, so that before a colleague knew what was happening, he or she was challenged into performing at a level not previously thought possible. And once that level was established those demands were never relaxed. The atmosphere was exhilarating.
His best-known research joined the paleomagnetism and radiometric ages of rocks collected from different parts of the world to find that before 700,000 years ago the geometric field had pointed south instead of north. Since the reversals were found to occur simultaneously everywhere, the polarity of the entire planetary field must have reversed. Together with his colleagues, by 1966 he had established a radiometric polarity time scale for the past 4,500,000 years and had concluded that polarity changes had occurred at an average rate of 5 reversals per million years. They found that the time intervals between successive reversals were highly variable in length, the shortest being less that than 50,000 years and the longest greater than 1,000,000 years.
He died January 27, 1987, in a bicycle accident near his home in Skylonda.
Description of the Collection
Papers document his professional life as teacher, administrator, and researcher and include correspondence; memoranda; research notes, charts, proposals, and reports; grant applications; outlines, tests, lecture notes, and other teaching materials; manuscripts; minutes; date books; papers and theses by his students; reprints; maps; and his notes while a student at UC Berkeley. Cox studied paleomagnetism and plate tectonics theory; some materials pertain to research done on the Galapagos Islands and in China.
List of common abbreviations
AAAS American Association for the Advancement of Science
ACS American Chemical Society
AGU American Geophysical Union
CGU Canadian Geophysical Union
ERDA Energy Research and Development Administration
G Geophysics (course number)
GEO Geology (course number)
GP Geophysics (course number)
GSA Geological Society of America
JGG Journal of Geomagnetism and Geoelectricity
JGR Journal of Geophysical Research
MAG Magnometer
NAS National Academy of Sciences
NOAA National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration
NRC National Research Council
NSF National Science Foundation
OPLAR Oceanic Plateaus Research
PEPS Paleomagnetic Euler Poles
PRF Petroleum Research Fund
China -- Geophysics.; Plate tectonics; Paleomagnetism.; Galapagos Islands -- Geophysics.; Geophysics.; Cox, Allan; Stanford University. Department of Geophysics. Faculty; Cox, Allan; Stanford University. School of Earth Sciences
- Papers
  - GEU 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Paleomag Reading Lists (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - GP 102 Notes (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1974 MT (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Class Notes 1 GP 102 Definitions (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Equal Area Nets (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Prob 5 - Solution (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lab Notes (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Converting XYZ to NED (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Orientation (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Problem 5 - Finite Rotations (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pr. 3 Solution (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Class Notes 3 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Solution to 2 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - G 102 Midterm - Old (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Notes on DRM (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Beok (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - G 102 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Revised Strat: Reading List. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Old Material (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - GP 152 1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Ishikawa, Y. GP 150 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Dickinson's Handouts (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Mid-Term - G 150 - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - GP 150 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Lecture Notes PT (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - GP 150 Syllabus (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - GP 150 Take Home Exam (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - PT 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - GP 150 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - GP 150 1978 Final Exam (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - GP 150 Final 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Course Evaluations (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - GP 150 M.T. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - MAG Prob 2 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - GP 190 MAG Prob (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - GP 190 MAG Lab (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - GP 190 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - [Unlabelled Notes] (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - [Unlabelled Notes] (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Sacks, I.S. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Exams (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - PS 1 1974 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - GP 190 Exam (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - GP 190 Student Evamluations (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1976 Notes (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - S. Ugeda (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1974 MT (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - G 190 - 1974 Class Notes 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Class Notes 1974 Master (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Class Notes Pre '74 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Problems Pre '74 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 190 - Problem Solutions Pre '74 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - George's Lectures (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - New Master (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - [Loose Material] (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Ditto Masters (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - [Loose Material] (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Lab #1 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Blakely GP 240 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bott (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bott and Hutton (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Bott and Hutton (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bullard et. al. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Caner (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Clarke (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Elasser (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Emilia and Bodvarsson (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Emilia and Bodvarsson (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Henderson (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Henderson (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Henderson and Wilson (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Henderson and Wilson (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Hubert (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Johnson (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Kanasewich et. al. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Linsser (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Naidu (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Reford and Sumner (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Rikitake and H. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Spector and Grant (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Talwani (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Uyeda and Richards (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Vacquier (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Zietz and Andreasen (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - 250 Exams (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Grades 1975 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - 250 problems (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - 250 Problems Dittos (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - G 250 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - GP 250 1971 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Class Notes (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - GP 250 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - [Unlabelled] (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - 250 Red Tape (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - 1070 Student Outlines of Papers Read (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Programs (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Illustrations for Projector (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - 250 - Class Notes (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Reading Lists (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Backus - Gilbert Version (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Aero Service (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - [Loose Papers] (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Resources (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - [Loose Papers] (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - [Unlabelled] (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Units (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - E&M Review (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 122B (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Plate Tec. China Caper - Sept. 79 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Oct 79 Penrose Conf. Washington (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Salvation - Aug. 6 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - May '79 - U. of Toronto - Wilson Symp. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Hawaii, July 1979 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - May 1979 - Spain (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - CGU - JUNE 4, '79 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - UCSB Lecture 2/20/79 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Nov. 9 - W.D.C. Greens (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Nov. 10 Ohio (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - June 15 '78 - Paris (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - June 1978 Unitarians - RC (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - May '79 - JT Wilson Univ. of Toronto (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - May Wester Wash (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - CGU - May 1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - March 29 U. of Calgary (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - March 1977 Silliman Lectures - Yale (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Verhoogen (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - M.E. Buck - Paleomagnetism of Upper Triassic Diabase (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Doell - Paleomag. of Volcanic Rocks from N.N AND N. Islands (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - [Unlabelled] (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Brinden (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Gore and Helsley (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - CRB Listen a Detailed Study of Ridge Flank Structure (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Lowrie and Fuller (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - MacDonald and Opdyke Lecture Rotations (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Merrill and Johnson JGR (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Ozima and Sakamoto (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - JGR - PORATH (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Strangway and McMahon (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Van der Voo: Paleomagnetic Study (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Oziwa (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Naidu (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - General Correspondence JGG (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - JGG - Denham (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - JGG Aoki (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Ozima and Aoki (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - C. Baag JGG (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - JGR - Reviews (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - EPSL MS Reviews (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - MS Reviews General (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Abstracts and Reviews - Old (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Proposal - Reviews - General - 1975-1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - NSF Proposal Reviews: 1975-78 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - National Science Foundation Proposals Reviews by Cox through 1974 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Proposals General 1975 only (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bureaucracy of Reversals (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Bowie Medal (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Schnapp (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Cox Paleolatitudes - Final Draft (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Majors (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Bowin, C.O. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Phillips (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Phillips et. al. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Phillips (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - History of Plate Tectonics (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Kenneth B. Baker (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Bloxsom, E. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Buhrman (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Brown, D. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Brown, Dave (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Burch, S.H. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Butler, A. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Butler, R. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Childs 102 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Cole, Searight and Bally (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Curry (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Courtillot (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Courtillot (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Foster Curry (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - John Decker (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Demitrack (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Jim Dick (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Duncan (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Eichel Berger 102 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Eugebreston, D. (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - FULP (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Gallinatti, J. (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Gordon, Richard (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Rhea Graham (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Greaves (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Green and MCW (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Grey (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - HAAR (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hansen (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Bill Harbert (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Hillhouse 102 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - George Hinton (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Howell (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Isaacs (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 12 Mirian, D. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Karish, C. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Kantor (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Keller (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Kennedy, M. and Jan Morton (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Kjartansson, E. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Kodama (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Lee, L. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - MacAskill (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - McCardle 102 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Mahren (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Metcalf (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Morton, Jan (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Monday (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Oppenheimer, D. [empty] (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Jeff Noblett (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - O'Hare (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Typescript: Contained in a binder this is a manuscript with no obvious title the subject is clearly Geomagnetism. The first chapter, The Earth's Present Field, the book goes on to discuss specific examples which illustrate aspects of the earth's magnetic past (I think). (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Geomagnetic Secular Variation and the Kinematics of the Earth's Core by John Ratcliffe Booker - a dissertation submitted in partial satisfaction of the requirements for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy in Earth Sciences at the UC San Diego. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - The Origin of the Bering Sea Marginal Basin - Implications from Marine Magnetic Data by Alan Kent Cooper; A dissertation submitted to the Department of Geophysics and the Committee on Graduate Studies of Stanford University in partial fulfillment fo the requirements fro the degree of Doctor of Philosophy (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Program Documentatio for Programs Comparing Paleomagnetic Data to Hypothetical Terrane Displacement Histories (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Report on the Ore Deposits of the Georgetown Colo. District - Geology 267 by J.A. Marsh (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - History of the Kula Plate: 78-43 Ma by Robert Brian Hart from the Stanford Circum Pacific Plate Tectonics Project (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Late Tertiary Faults in South-Central Alaska by Nicholas B. Harris (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - A Comparison Between Natural and Laboratory Oxidation of Titanomagnetite in Pillow Lavas by Patrick J.C. Ryall - Submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy at Dalhousie University (December 1974) (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Sears (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Simpson (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Snyder (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Stratton (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Suczek (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Turin (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Elastic Properties of a Composite Material: The Numerical Approach by Robert M. Uleman - MS thesis in Geophysics at Stanford (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Ulmer (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Wallace, Mark (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - White 102 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Wilson, D.S. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - K. Winkler (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Zoback (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Holcomb (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Jarrard (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Prevost (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Stratton (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Talawi, D. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Wilderness Areas (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Wang (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Sigma Xi Lecture (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Expenses 1981 Sierra Nevada (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Kenya '75 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Receipts and Log (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Kenya Trip [unlabeled] (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Sequoia (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Lost Samples (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - N.M. Laschamb (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Ariz Laschamb (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Kyoto 1973 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Motor Drives (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - DES/NAS (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Canadian Trip 1974 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - 1973 Sept-Dec (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Pygmy Forest (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Sampling Areas - Rotations (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Tillamook (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Sampling Plans (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Computer Maps (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - NSF (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - GSA Travel (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Auto Rental (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Mater Charge (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Stanford Policies (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Stanford Per Diem (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - U.S.G.S. Per Diem (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - 1971 Summer (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - A Proposal to Join the Stanford Oceanic Plateaus Research (OPLAR) Project (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Pygmy Forest Samples (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - OPLAR (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Coast Range Ophiolite (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Aleutians (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Paleomag. Invest. Allocations Terranes New (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - NSF Paleomag Major Tectonic Elements of Eastern China 6/81 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - P. Studies Ancient Plate Velocities (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Paleomag. Test Possible Notation of Sierra Nevada (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - ACS-PRF #11405-AC2 Paleomag. and Tectonics of Basin (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - NSF EAR 78-14781 Cordelleran Paleomag: Late Precambrian Glaciation and Polar Wandering (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - NSF Paleomag. and Tectonics of Eocene Crescent From ... SW (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Washington Coast Range (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - NSF - EAR76 - 00120 2-BCZ-429 Paleomag. Tectonic Investigation of Oregon (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Oregon Lecture Framework of W. Cascades from ... Microplate Boundary (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - NSF 79-10032 Pleomag. Study Radiocarbon Dated Hawaiian Lavas (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - NSF 77-13640 Paleomag. Investigation of Cordilleran Tectonics (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - NSF76-12576 Equipment Grant (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - NSF DES 74-23123 (2-BC2-424) Paleomag Investigation of Fine Structure of Geomagnetic Field (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - HEW (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - NSF EAR79-11136 Paleomag. Studies of Ancient Plate Velocities (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - ERDA Travelship Proposals (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - ERDA Geothermal Energy Proposal (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Orienting Samples (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Budget (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Tekiroux Plotter (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Absolute Euler Poles from APW Curves (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - MAG Sign-up (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Beck/Plumbley (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Clarno FM (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - NSF Summary Report (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Physics-Cryogenics (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Fast MG (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - DEMAG (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Plotting (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - STC (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Tilamook Volc (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - SU (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Dynamo (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - B.M. Transitions (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - J.D. Clark (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Rock Drill (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - VRM-DRM Well Log Tool (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Collecting Samples (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Geller - NSF Investigations of Q... (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - DSDP (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Deformations (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Laetoli Research (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - ScT (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - NDOMB (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Brownian Movement (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - E. Rudolf Reprints (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Wilson CK Formations GP 102 Results (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - AFD Disc System (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Equipment Catalogues (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Sponsored Research (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Joab's Sample (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Meteorite Proposal (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Mag. Anomalies (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Quaternary Sections (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Seesmie Data (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - NSF Equipment (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Kenya (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - E. Rudolf (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Africa Laschamp (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Bureaucracy of Mag. Reversals (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - DRF Proposal (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Index Headings (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Courtillot (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - SJC (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Torroidal Fluxgate (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Phillips (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Graham (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Oregon - Eocene (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Sabbatical (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - NOAA Data (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - G 331 Seminar (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Kyoto Meeting (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Kenya (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Shielding (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - NASA Exp (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - NSF- Short Events (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Lamont Data (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Change in 8squared (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Allende (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - 1972 AGU (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Dr. Speed (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Spinner Checks (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - NSF Proposal 1968 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - CMR (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Mag. Data Production (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Stanford Lawyer vol. 20 no. 2 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Stanford Lawyer vol. 21 no. 1 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Agenda Stanford University Board of Trustees (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - MSEX (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Gordon (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Physics Students (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - EG-Promotion (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Stanford Gen'l (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - IES (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Sabbaticals (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Chinese Visitors (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - SCEIT 1979 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - 1978 SCEIT (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Faculty Club (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Department (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Dept. Gen'l. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - General Deanship (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Deanship (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Old (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Course Enrollment (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Paleomag. Position (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Search Com. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Scholarship Possibilities (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - New Student Visits (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - 1928 Students (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Geop Quals. 1977 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Research (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Letter for New Dean Search Comm. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Research (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Am. Assoc. Univ. Professors (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Sigma Xi (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Und. Spec. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Farrell - Scire (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Annual Behavior and e.g. Prediction (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Bookstore (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Lights Project (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - General (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Hours/Receipts (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - TP Summaries (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Corres (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Geology 107 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - [unlabeled] (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Schedule (check list) (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Outline (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Permissions (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Req. for Preprints (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Chapt. 2 Solutions (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Cartoon Ideas (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Chpt. 6 Figs. New (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Box Frames (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - HP-33E Programs (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Alvares PT Review (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - China Papers (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - OGG (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Plate Tectonics Student Evaluations (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Plate Tectonics Expenses (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Terrane Trajectories and Plate Interactions Along Continental Margins in the North Pacific Basin (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Paper 3 Xerox Masters (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Terrane Trajectory Analysis (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Laytonville Figure Drafting 6/13/85 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Von Huene (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Smith, James Stephen - Geophysics Aut. 1985 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Terrane Trajectory Analysis Paper III for AC Review (Box 19, Folder 14)